## JAS DOYLE-PITT

Self Shooter / Editor / AP/ Researcher

Contact +447800883585 LONDON, N16

jasdoylepitt@gmail.com

#### References

Andre Singer
Executive Producer,
Spring Films
47 Conduit Street
London W1S 2YP | UK
http://www.springfilms.tv/
+44 (0) 20 3327 4930
andre.singer@springfilms.tv

Paul Berczeller Writer/ Director http://www.berczeller.com paul@berczeller.com

Simon Oatley
Head of BFI Film Academy,
VFX Speciality Course
CEO Film and Video
Workshop,
Hungerford School,
Hungerford Road, N7 9LF
http://www.filmworkshop.com
simon@filmworkshop.com

Dick Fontaine
Head of Documentary,
National Film and Television
School,
Beaconsfield Studios, 141
Station Rd, Beaconsfield
HP9 1LG
DFontaine@nfts.co.uk

#### **Profile**

I am a technically competent, confident, self-shooter and editor. I have worked between commercial videography and creative short films for the last 6 years in the UK and internationally. For the last two years I have produced and directed a number of short documentary films as part of an MA with the National Film and Television School. I am used to working in high-pressure environments and always get on with the crew, cast, or contributors I am working with. I have strong visual ideas, and am able to channel the ideas of others. I am a confident editor. I have a good knowledge of the post-production process, and can both manage my own projects, and work within a big post machine. I have a strong access history, over the last three years I have gained access to two prisons in Bolivia, secure teenage care units in London, counsel offices, sports organisations, schools, and a crematorium. I am looking to work within an experienced team, with a company producing innovative work.

#### Skills

- Camera/Lighting
- Observational documentary shooting handheld, easyrig, and tripod.
- Interview set up and lighting including using an Interrotron.
- Camera: C300, FS7, most Panasonic models, Black Magic Pocket, Atom 16/35mm, 360°.
- Camera assistant: Focus puller, DIT.
- Lighting: Documentary and interview.
- Editing
- Experience with short form narrative (2 years)
- Trailers and commercials (4 years)
- Final Cut X (6 years), Premier Pro (4 years), and Avid (2 years).
- Editing assistant: logging, transcribing, syncing, data wrangling, subtitling.
- Directing
- Factual, interviews, commercials, music videos.
- Crew, actors, composers, sound mixes, grades.
- Commercial Videography: Studio set ups/ live streaming/ corporate conference and events setups.
- Sound
- Onboard sound/ radio mic set-up, external multi-mic (rig) with basic mixing.
- VFX and graphics
- Aftereffects: graphics, grading, masks, basic animation.
- Animation: Dragon Frame and Flash
- Written skills
- Treatments, grant proposals, narrative scripts, commercial scripts.
- Research: Factual (journalistic), brand and science based.
- Producing/AP
- Strong access skills
- Organizing and budgeting 1-day to 3-month shoots.
- Other skills:
- Languages: English, Intermediate Spanish.

#### Education

Directing Documentary, MA, National Film and Television School (2016-2018) Psychology, BsC 1st Class Hons, University of Sussex, (2009-2012)

#### Selected Filmography

<u>'Abrázame, Hold me'</u> Director / Producer / Camera/ Editor (Jan 2017- Jan 2018)

A life behind bars is seen through the eyes of children, who are growing up living inside Bolivia's notoriously dangerous prisons.

Link: <a href="https://vimeo.com/250615940">https://vimeo.com/250615940</a> Password: nfts

**'Former Relevant Child'** Director/ Producer/ Camera (Jul 2017- Jan 2017)
Two girls contemplate their life growing up in care, and their uncertain futures after they are declared adults on their 18<sup>th</sup> birthdays. Link: <a href="https://vimeo.com/213647896/767e2196e6">https://vimeo.com/213647896/767e2196e6</a>

**'Drift'** Director/ Producer/ Camera (March 2017- July 2017) Adult siblings reflect on growing in the care system through puppetry.

Link: <a href="https://vimeo.com/244855808">https://vimeo.com/244855808</a> Password: Drift

**'Kids on Gender'** Director/ Producer/ Camera (Jan 2014- Dec 2015)

Children grapple with the slippery concept of gender. Link: <a href="https://vimeo.com/106958727">https://vimeo.com/106958727</a>

## JAS DOYLE-PITT

Self Shooter / Editor / AP/ Researcher

Contact +447800883585 LONDON, N16 jasdoylepitt@gmail.com

### Work History

#### Commercial Videography: Director/Producer/Editor

(Jan 2016- Jan 2018)

Working with clients to produce, direct and edit short online commercial films. Clients include BFI, Stanford Business University, Dazed Digital, Selfridges, One Thought, and Cut films. Links available on request.

# BFI Film Academy: Head of Production, VFX and Animation Tutor (Jan 2015- Oct 2017)

Managing students and tutors of 12 VFX, live action, and animation productions from conception to delivery on a one-week schedule. In the past I worked as a tutor directly teaching techniques, developing ideas, and teaching software quickly, and on the go.

#### References

Andre Singer
Executive Producer,
Spring Films
47 Conduit Street
London W1S 2YP | UK
http://www.springfilms.tv/
+44 (0) 20 3327 4930
andre.singer@springfilms.tv

Paul Berczeller Writer/ Director http://www.berczeller.com

paul@berczeller.com

Simon Oatley
Head of BFI Film Academy,
VFX Speciality Course
CEO Film and Video
Workshop,
Hungerford School,
Hungerford Road, N7 9LF
http://www.filmworkshop.com
simon@filmworkshop.com

Dick Fontaine
Head of Documentary,
National Film and Television
School,
Beaconsfield Studios, 141
Station Rd, Beaconsfield
HP9 1LG
DFontaine@nfts.co.uk

#### Film and Video Workshop: Project Manager

Working alongside partners such as BFI and Creative Skillset to deliver a wide range of educational film projects including VFX courses, live action projects, and stop motion animation film workshops. Duties included writing grant applications, recruiting for courses, and budgeting projects. I also managed our kit hire for all students, involving buying and selling new/old kit and managing our internal systems.

#### Snatch Documentaries Ltd: Director

(Sept 2013- Sept 2014)

(July 2014- Dec 2016)

Set-up and ran a small production company for female led short films, and for commercial work. Worked with a young team of five passionate artists and spent a year creating beautiful films which screened internationally in festivals before we ran out of money and rent became too expensive.

### NGO Videographer, Sustainable Bolivia

(July 2013- Dec 2016)

Videography services (directing, producing, editing) several promotional short films over a six month period for NGO's associated with Sustainable Bolivia, an international volunteer organization. Film were promotional and for online delivery.

#### Voluntary Work

(July 2011- Present)

Youth Worker: Forest School Camps

Annually I work as a youth leader in an outdoor adventure setting (usually Wales/ The Highlands or similar). Specific challenges are outdoor survival, teenagers, and leading a team of staff who are wet and cold.

Drugs and Alcohol Services Volunteer: 'After Party' LGBT services

I worked for Lifeline, Hackney drugs services , as a volunteer drugs worker for LGBT clients through the breakaway service 'Afterparty'. Mainly we gave out needles, condoms, advice on Chemsex and signposting where to get help in other LGBT+ friendly services.

Programming Assistant: Fringe Queer Film and Arts Festival

I was responsible for programing the shorts programs for Fringe! (2013). I watched over 3000 submissions and curated shorts programs.

Development Videographer, Hyderabad.

Worked with women's development NGO to create online content for funding for the charity MSF Foundation (Sept 2012- Feb 2013)